<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Personal website of Loïc Davadan</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Personal website of Loïc Davadan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>First tests in mlr</title>
      <link>/post/visualize_maps_prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/visualize_maps_prediction/</guid>
      <description>I detailed before in this post why we use mlr in the context of the AGROMET project. Machine learning is very powerful to build models.
I will present my methods and my results.
Data preparation Reshaping data I have already explained it in my last post but this is an important part of the workflow.
mlr package needs a data frame to work correctly. Then, we need to focus on its preparation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to machine learning in R</title>
      <link>/post/introduction_mlr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/introduction_mlr/</guid>
      <description>When I began my internship in the CRA-W, I had no idea of what machine learning was. Its weight in the AGROMET project required from me that I learn basis and some applications to apply it in R.
That’s why, writing a brief introduction on machine learning and on its utilisation in R seems to be a good idea.
What is machine learning ? Machine learning is a subset of deep learning or Artificial Intelligence that provides an ability to “learn” with data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get solar irradiance data from Wallonia</title>
      <link>/post/get_solar_irradiance_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/get_solar_irradiance_data/</guid>
      <description>Solar irradiance is a parameter of interest for building models to predict weather parameters like temperature. That’s why we need to access to these data and prepare them to be included in the models.
Get data To obtain solar irradiance data from Wallonia, those have been included in the AGROMET API from EUMETSAT website. Data that we have are DSSF (Downward Surface Shortwave Flux) with a frequency of 1 day (MDSSF) or 30 minutes (DIDSSF) and measured in W/m².</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Methodology to prepare CLC and DMT data</title>
      <link>/post/methodology_clc_topo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/methodology_clc_topo/</guid>
      <description>In the context of the AGROMET project, we need CORINE land cover data and digital terrain model to improve models.
I refer you to my other posts about CORINE land cover (CLC) :
 How to get CLC data from Wallonia
 Solve a problem in computing the area of each polygon inside a buffer
  This post deals with the methodology which was applied to prepare data before using them in our models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solve a problem in computing the area of each polygon inside a buffer</title>
      <link>/post/solve_pb_clc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/solve_pb_clc/</guid>
      <description>In the context of the AGROMET project, we searched to include data from CORINE land cover in our models. I refer you to my post How to get CORINE land cover data from Wallonia where I explained how we got data and how we reclass land covers in groups.
During my work, I wanted to calculate the part of each land cover around every station and I am arrived at a problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to get CORINE land cover data from Wallonia</title>
      <link>/post/get_corinelc_wallonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/get_corinelc_wallonia/</guid>
      <description>The objective of the AGROMET project is to provide hourly 1km² gridded datasets of weather parameters with the best accuracy (i.e. spatialize hourly records from the stations on the whole area of Wallonia). Weather parameters will be predicted with explanatory variables. These explanatory variables are :
 Digital elevation model and its derivatives like aspect and slope
 Solar irradiance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to build a template map with data of AGROMET stations</title>
      <link>/post/creating_map/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/creating_map/</guid>
      <description>One of the objectives of the AGROMET project is to make maps to view spatialized data. That’s why I tried to create a template map to view the different tests of spatialization.
To do that, I used data from the AGROMET API using methods I have already detailed before.
Get map of Wallonia Source : Raster data acquisition
We need an outline map to limit the map to Wallonia. We can get the font of Wallonia with getData() function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working environment</title>
      <link>/post/working_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/working_environment/</guid>
      <description>In the context of my internship, my work mainly consists in development. However, working in development often imposes to be methodic.
That’s why, when I have began my internship, I installed my working environment to be more productive.
Installing Linux First, I have installed Ubuntu GNOME, a distribution of Linux on my laptop. Indeed, this OS is prefered by developers and open-source addicts thanks to the high contribution to improve distributions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First experience with the API</title>
      <link>/post/load_data_frasnes_hra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/load_data_frasnes_hra/</guid>
      <description>The API has 20 years of records of weather data. When you need some data, you have to use the API to load them.
For my first exercise, I had to give an usable file with data about the relative humidity throughout the year near to Frasnes-lez-Anvaing.
Find the nearest station Fisrt, I checked where was Frasnes-lez-Anvaing on the platform to find the nearest station.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentation of the internship</title>
      <link>/post/internship_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/internship_presentation/</guid>
      <description>In the course of my studies in Bordeaux Sciences Agro, I realised a 3-month internship. This internship took place in the Walloon agricultural research centre (CRA-W)) from May 22nd to August 20th 2018. I made a contribution to the AGROMET project in Farming Systems, Territory and Information Technologies Unit. The aim of the Agromet project is to provide a near real-time hourly gridded datasets of weather parameters at the resolution of 1 km² for the whole region of Wallonia characterized by a quality indicator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources about Spatialization, R and others</title>
      <link>/post/resources_documents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/resources_documents/</guid>
      <description>Last update : 20/06/2018 This post will sum up a few sources of information useful if you are interested in spatialization or development.
 Spatialization and GIS Definition : Spatialization or spatial interpolation creates a continuous surface from values measured at discrete locations to predict values at any location in the interest zone with the best accuracy.
The book Using ArcGIS Geostatistical Analyst will give you an efficient overview about spatialization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AGROMET API to get weather data</title>
      <link>/post/store_api-token/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/store_api-token/</guid>
      <description>An API (Application Programming Interface) allows connections to be established between several software programs to exchange data. It needs the authentification of the user with a API key or token. Storing the API key in a script enables to call it in other commands to modify the files of the API. This token will not be available for other users, avoiding in that way an abusive use of this key by others.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>